Hello, and welcome to Problem Session 8 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好 这是 Wolfram U 微积分入门的习题课 8
The topic for this session is area between curves and volume.
本次习题课的主题是曲线间的面积和体积
The first few problems are about areas,
前几个是关于面积的
and the next few problems are about volumes.
后几个是关于体积的
Let’s begin with problem number 1,
从问题 1 开始
which says compute the area between the curves f and g
计算 f 和 g 之间的区域面积
given by x^2 – 2 and x^3 + x + 7 between the limits –1 and 3 for x.
函数关于 x 是 x^2 – 2 和 x^3 + x + 7 在 -1 与 3 之间
Here is a plot of the functions,
这儿是函数的图像
and it’s clear that the orange line is above,
很明显橙色线在上面
but that corresponds to g, so g is greater than f in the region.
但是他是 g 的线 所以 g 比 f 高 在该区域上
The area would be the integral of g minus f from –1 to 3.
面积是 g 减 f 在 –1 到 3 间的积分
Simplify a bit, and that is the answer for the area.
化简后 这个答案就是面积
Problem number 2 says find the area
问题 2 来计算面积
enclosed by these two curves over here.
被这两条曲线包围
Again the functions are given to you,
函数给你了
but you’re not given the points of intersection,
但是没有给出交点
so let’s find them with Solve.
所以我们要用 Solve 来算
Those are the intersection points.
这俩是交点
Next you plot to get a geometrical picture,
然后你画一个图
and it’s clear now that the –x^2 – 2 is the one that’s dominating,
很明显现在 –x^2 – 2 是主要的那个
so f is greater than g, so you must do f minus g in the integral.
所以 f 比 g 大 所以在积分里必须是 f 减 g
You do that for the given limits,
按算的积分限做
and then you get the answer for the integral.
然后就能得到积分的答案
Problem number 3 is the same kind of thing,
问题 3 差不多
but now with x in terms of y.
但是把 x 换成了 y
You’ve got two functions of y, 2y + 4 and y^3 – y,
有两个 y 的函数 2y + 4 和 y^3 – y
between the limits –2 and 2.
在 -2 到 2 之间
You need to use ParametricPlot to get the correct picture,
需要用 ParametricPlot 来画正确的图像
and when you do that, it’s clear that f is greater than g
并且当这么做时 显然 f 大于 g
because f is to the right of g.
是因为 f 在 g 右边
You work out f minus g between the limits,
计算上下限之间 f 减 g 的积分
and here is the answer for the integral.
这是积出来的结果
Problem number 4 is about two functions of y,
问题 4 是两个关于 y 的函数
but again this time you’re not given the points of intersection,
但是依然没给出交点
so you want to find the area enclosed between them.
然后你想要找到他们之间的封闭区域
You use the Solve function to find where they intersect.
用 Solve 算出他们的交点
Here is a parametric plot showing you what happens,
这是一个参数图 显示怎么样了
and it’s clear that g this time is greater than f,
显然 这次 g 比 f 大
so you do g minus f and compute the integral,
所以做的是 g 减 f 的积分
and you get back the answer for the area between those two curves.
然后得到两条曲线间的面积
Number 5. Now we’re on to volumes.
问题 5 现在是体积的问题
You’re given a solid with hexagonal cross sections,
这有一个具有六边形横截面的固体
and you’re told that the area of those cross sections
截面面积给你了
is given by 6√3x^2.
是 6√3x^2
The question is to find the volume of the solid from 0 to 5.
问题是这个固体在 0 到 5 之间的体积
Here’s a plot, but it doesn’t really matter what the details are;
这是示意图 细节不重要
the main point is you have a formula for the volume
关键是你有计算体积的公式
as the integral from a to b of the area.
是这个面积从 a 到 b 的积分
In this case, you have 0 to 5 of the area,
这里 是 0 到 5 之间的面积
and that’s easy to compute,
很容易算出
so you get back the volume in this example.
这个例子的体积
On to number 6, where you’re asked to find the volume
问题 6 计算体积
of this rather difficult-looking solid
这个看起来很难的固体
which has a base which is a semicircle.
他的地面是半圆
You can see it over here.
可以在这看到他
You want to compute the volume for this solid
要算这个固体的体积
when the cross sections are equilateral triangles.
他的横截面是等边三角形
Now that’s the difficult part.
现在这里很难
How do you compute the area of each cross section?
怎么算每个横截面的面积
Well, the area for an equilateral triangle is x^2(√3/4),
好吧 等边三角形的面积是 x^2(√3/4)
but x in this case is just the semicircle function over here,
但是 x 在这里是半圆的函数
so the area is (36 – x^2)(√3/4).
所以面积是 (36 – x^2)(√3/4)
Work out the limits, but those are the limits
算上下限 然后这些是上下限
where the semicircle cuts the x axis, which are –6 and 6,
半圆切割了 x 轴 即在 –6 和 6之间
so that’s the area to compute.
这就是要计算的区域
Work it out and you get the required volume.
算出来就能得到体积
Okay. On to number 7, which says compute the volume of the solid
好 问题 7 计算这个固体的体积
which is created when the region bounded by
创建的区域收到边界限制
this function and the x axis is revolved around the x axis.
由这个函数 并且绕 x 轴旋转
That’s the plot of the solid, and the point over here is that
这是固体的图 重点是
you have a semicircle of radius 2, so the endpoints of the integral
你有一个半径为 2 的半圆 所以积分的端点
will be –2 and 2 because that’s where
是 -2 和 2 因为这是
the semicircle intersects the x axis.
半圆和 x 轴的交点
Now apply the disk method, so you chop the solid up into small disks,
现在用圆盘法 将固体切为小圆盘
and each disk has the √(4 – x^2) as the radius, so it’s πr^2.
每个圆盘的半径是 √(4 – x^2) 所以面积是 πr^2
Work out the volume with the disk method, and that’s the answer.
用圆盘法计算 这就是答案
Now of course in this simple case, you have a ball with a radius 2,
当然 简单的时候 当球半径是 2 的时候
so its volume is 4(r^3)π/3.
他的体积是 4(r^3)π/3
That’s just the same result that we got
这和我们的结果一样
a little while ago using Integrate.
前一阵子用 Integrate 算过
On to number 8, which says find the volume of the solid created
问题 8 求这个固体体积 他是这样构造的
between this function over here
由这个函数生成
and the x axis-bounded rotate from –π to π.
绕 x 轴旋转 在 –π 到 π 之间
Okay. Again over here use the disk method.
好 再次使用圆盘法
When you use the disk method, you see that each cross section
在用圆盘法的时候 会看到每个横截面
has got radius (xSin[x])^2,
的半径是 (xSin[x])^2
so you work out the volume with the disk method in this case.
所以你可以用圆盘法来计算这个体积
Okay. On to a similar kind of calculation, but now for y functions.
好的 算个差不多的 但现是 y 的函数
You have a region that’s bounded by 2y^2 on the y axis,
你在 y 轴上有一个以 2y^2 为边界的有界区域
and you want to work out the volume of the solid from y = 1 to y = 3.
然后要计算 y = 1 到 y = 3 之间的体积
That’s the picture of the solid.
这是固体的图像
Apply the disk method, but this time the radius is 2y^2.
由圆盘法 这次的半径是 2y^2
Use the formula for the disk method,
利用圆盘法的公式
and you get back the volume.
就能得到体积
Okay. On to number 10, which says compute the volume of the solid
问题 10 计算这个体积
created when the region bounded by 2x and (x^2)/3
由这个在 2x 和 (x^2)/3 之间的有界区域生成
from x = 0 to x = 6 is revolved around the x axis.
从 x = 0 到 x = 6 绕 x 轴旋转
Now there are two functions over here.
这儿有两个函数
When you plot over here, you see you’ve got a region
画出来 你就能看到这个区域
bounded by two functions,
被这两个函数包围
and that’s a good case to apply the washer method to.
这是个很好的使用垫圈法的例子
We apply the washer method.
用垫圈法
The outer radius is 2x from here.
外半径是 2x
The inner radius is (x^2)/3.
内半径是 (x^2)/3
You simply apply a difference of the radii square over here,
简单的将半径做差
so you get π times the outer radius squared
然后得到 π 乘 这个外半径方
minus the inner radius squared and work out the volume
减内半径方 得到体积
with the washer method.
用垫圈法
On to number 11, which talks about find the volume created
问题 11 算这个体积 这样构造的
when the region bounded by (y^4)/8 and 2y^2 from those two limits
有界区域被 (y^4)/8 和 2y^2 这两个函数限制
is revolved around the y axis.
绕 y 轴旋转
Here’s a plot.
这是图
Once again, what you need to do is to apply the washer method
还是 你要做的就是应用垫圈法
because you’ve got two functions.
因为你有两个函数
Apply the washer method, compute the volume
用垫圈法 算体积
by doing π times the difference of the squares of the radii,
通过 π 去乘 半径平方的差
and that gives the answer for the volume.
得到这个答案
Okay. On to number 12, and that’s about computing the volume
好 问题 12 计算这个体积
of the solid created when the region bounded by this function
由这个函数下的区域生成
and the x axis and the lines given over here
给出 x 轴和这条线
is revolved around the y axis.
绕 y 轴旋转
Now the point here is the y axis,
现在这点是 y 轴
so you need to apply the cylindrical shell method.
因此你需要用柱壳法
Okay. That’s the solid over here.
好 这就是固体
You break it up into small cylinders, and keep in mind that
把他分解成小圆柱 并且记住
for a cylinder method, you have to have 2πrh
对于柱壳法 必须有 2πrh
where h is the function definition.
这里 h 是函数高
So you do that and you get the volume back,
这样你就可以得到体积
but this time using the cylindrical shell method
但是这次使用柱壳法
because you are revolving around the y axis, not the x axis.
因为你是绕 y 轴 而不是 x 轴
Number 13 says find the volume of the solid created
问题 13 算这个体积他是构造出来的
when the region bounded by this, the y axis
有界区域是这样的 y 轴
and the two values given over here is revolved around the x axis.
和这儿给的两个值之间 绕 x 轴旋转
Once again, that’s the plot, but apply the cylindrical shell method
再说一次 这是图像 但是要用柱壳法
because you have revolving around the x rather than the y axis.
因为你是绕 x 轴而不是 y 轴旋转
You do 2πrh where r is y and h is the function expression.
用 2πrh 这里 r 是 y h 是 函数值
Apply that and you get back the volume
用完后 就能算得体积
using the cylindrical shell method.
用柱壳法
Finally, on to number 14.
最后 问题 14
That says compute the volume of the solid created
算这个体积 这样构造的
when the region bounded by –x^2 + 2 and the x axis
区域在 –x^2 + 2 和 x 轴之间
is revolved around the line y = 4.
绕 y = 4 轴旋转
If you think about it, we’ll apply the disk method,
如果你思考一下 那么将用圆盘法
but this time the radii will be obtained
但是这次半径将
by subtracting the function value from 4
是 4 减去 函数值
because 4 is the line around which you are rotating, y = 4.
因为是绕 4 旋转的 所以 y = 4
Then you work out the endpoints, get the integral over here.
然后算出端点 得到积分
That’s πr^2dx.
就是 πr^2dx
Put in the limits, and you get back
给定上下限 就能得到
the answer for the volume in the disk method.
圆盘法下的体积
That brings me to the end of this problem session.
习题课到此结束
I hope you have learned these very important ideas,
我希望你能理解这些重要的思路
and I’ll see you next time.
我们下次见
Thank you.
再见
翻译：兰州大学 周怀尚